# BHARAT MEHRA

Ludhiana, India 141008 • 9464138852 • bharatmehra232@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven by a passion for innovation in gaming, I've excelled in roles up to Game Development Manager at WOF Productions, enhancing gameplay and cross-platform integration. My expertise in Unity and collaborative leadership have significantly boosted game performance and team productivity.

### EXPERIENCE

**Game Development Manager**, 07/2024 - Current **WOF Productions** - Chicago, United States

• WOF Arena - A freeform RNG 2D multiplayer idle game. Create characters based on items received randomly and win fights by RNG.

**Game Developer**, 01/2020 - Current **Upwork** - WFH, IN

- Star Square A 2D multiplayer puzzle game where players have to connect dots to lines to form a square, completing the board with the higher number of wins. This game has been created from scratch by me only; designs were provided by the client. Technologies used: Photon multiplayer, AI, Firebase, Unity, C#.
- Scared Tube. An AA 3D multiplayer FPS horror survival arcade game.
  Contains advanced functionalities like 4-player multiplayer, character customization, procedural environments, advanced ghost AI, HDR cutscenes using Unity Timeline, etc.
- Gabber Run A 3D HDR infinite runner game based on real-life DJs, with their support, has many features in the game, such as puzzles, character customizations, sound customizations, bosses, a battle pass system, and the management of a huge inventory. Everything is handled by the server, plus Addressables.
- + 6 to 7 Prototypes and minor projects which never published online or made to public access.

### Game Development Team Lead, 07/2023 - 06/2024

Apptunix - Mohali, IN

- Kina Pool A 3D multiplayer pool game, contains highly active AI and challenge modes, and allows you to play with friends. It also contains 8player tournaments.
- Halloween Promotional Event A promotional event featuring mini games that run on the web (HTML). Contains small rewards, like x% off on certain products from companies. Based on a Halloween theme.
- Relief Play An infinite runner 3D game whose basic motive is to provide education loans to students by playing the game.

### SKILLS

- Gameplay optimization
- Cross-platform development
- Game analytics analysis
- Technical documentation writing
- Unity 2D & 3D
- Advanced Animation Creation
- C# & C++
- Multiplayer development

### LANGUAGES

Hindi: First Language

English:

C2

Proficient (C2)

# • ACTIVITIES AND HOBBIES

- Gaming
- · Trekking and exploring
- Reading Books & researching topics

# PORTFOLIO

- Portfolio, PBX010
- Upwork Profile

 Various Products Metaverse - Made various 3D metaverses for various companies, showcasing their products in a 3D environment and letting users interact with them.

### Senior Game Developer, 10/2022 - 06/2023

Warlands NFT - Dubai, UAE

- Survivors vs. Zombies Survive waves of undead zombies. 3D roguelike game.
- Mini Pets Zombies A 3D simulation game for Android where people can take care of different animals by playing some mini-games.
- Warlands NFT A 3D Open World MOBA game. Totally based on NFT operations and inventory, I had a collaboration with many Web3 companies.

#### Game Developer, 10/2021 - 10/2022

Live Deftsoft Informatics - Mohali, IN

- Concert XL A 3D concert platform where bands can host different concerts based on YouTube videos. Sell-out tickets for the same, and multiplayer is available as well. Where people can join and enjoy the concert together in real time.
- FilmMaker Pro An advanced **AAA** software where users can make movies and animations using 3D models, animations, sounds, etc. Which gets uploaded online, and the same is fetched in the app and ready to use. Players can drop in stuff, and do what they want.

### **EDUCATION**

06/2021

**Bachelor of Technology**, Mechanical Engineering **Ludhiana College of Engg. & Technology**, Punjab Technical University

06/2017

+2, Non-Medical

Amrit Indo Canadian Academy, CBSE

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby certify that above information is correct and true to best of my knowledge and belief